With agents,
there's a behavior called reward seeking which is you ask them to do something
and they're really, really, really keen to do it.
And so they go up and they try to do everything they can,
and they escape their sandbox
and they delete files and they do whatever it is to please
If you cannot commit to the repository, fail.
Don't like go off and sort of send it in another way.
We need to move from securing the code to securing the coder, securing the
the agent.
the attack vector, but also the spectrum of what is there
is hard to follow and hard to secure because we want to enable
AI as a force multiplier.
But in the meantime we also have to mitigate the risk.
So we find ourselves in this kind of carrot and stick mode security.
If it doesn't become agentic, it will never keep up.
The AI Native Dev is a podcast for developers and engineering
leads at the cutting edge of AI and agentic coding.
Join your hosts, Guy Podjarny and me, Simon Maple.
Every week as we chat with the most exciting voices in
AI and tackle the biggest questions facing developers today.
This is the AI Native Dev.
Back in November,
we hosted the first ever in-person AI Native Dev con in New York.
This June 1st and second, we're bringing it to London.
It's two days built for AI Native developers and engineering teams, one day
full of hands on workshops and one day full of practical talks on
agent skills, context engineering, agent orchestration and enablement platforms
and how teams are actually shipping AI in production.
Join us at the Brewery in London near the Barbican for all of that,
plus networking parties, giveaways and a room full of people.
Building the future of AI Native Development.
You can also join us from anywhere in the world via the live stream.
As you're listening to this podcast.
You get 30% off your ticket with code POD30.
Just head to ainativedev.com and we'll see you in London.
Hey there, Simon Maple
here at the AI Security summit here in London.
This is a great conference to talk about all things security in AI development.
There are going to be practitioners,
and there are also going to be loads of CISOs and security leaders at this event.
Now Tessl's here, we've got a booth and we also have Guy here, previous
founder of Snyk as well as the founder of Tessl.
And Guy is going to be giving a session
talking about security keeping up with agentic development.
Let's secure not the code but the coder.
Because how can we make developers think more securely
when using agentic methods and agentic tooling?
Cool.
Let's see if we can talk to a couple of people while we're here.
So now I'm
here joined by Brian Vermeer, a Staff Developer Advocate at Snyk.
And we go back a long, long way.
Brian, you've been on the podcast before, and we're now here at your event.
What's your event called?
This event is called the AI Security Summit.
And what is it about?
Well, it's about AI and security.
I think the name says it all, but with AI,
there comes a lot of new security attack factors.
And what do you need to think about?
How do you need to transition from old fashioned to, say,
software dependency analysis and software code
analysis to now driving your code agent to creating your code,
but also things like skills and MCP and that kind of stuff.
So like shifting gears into that space of security.
Amazing.
And you actually gave the intro speech
at the at the leadership summit that we just had across the road.
also at the main event here.
What would you say the biggest issues that that are on
the CSO minds today when they're thinking about their organizations
trying to adopt and roll out AI really as fast as they possibly can?
What do people coming to you complaining about?
I think it's a very good question. I think it's multiple things.
First of all, people are not aware,
like what kind of AI is already in their systems.
They think they're not using any models or maybe even any MCP servers.
But in some cases, even your agent can decide to pull in a certain model
to get track of something else.
So things like shadow AI or
employees just using their own free ChatGPT account to do things.
So the attack vector, but also the spectrum of what is there
is hard to follow and hard to secure
because we want to enable AI as a force multiplier.
But in the meantime we also have to mitigate the risk.
And these are things that CISOs are challenged by.
So it's almost like a problem of discovery.
And this is really interesting
because this kind of like reminds me, if you think back around, you know,
I guess where Snyk originated from, when we look at dependencies
and trying to identify dependencies, what people are using in their organization,
a thing was created called a software bill of materials, where we kind of like
these are all the dependencies that we use.
Do you feel like something is equally needed now
from a from an AI point of view?
Like what are the things I like?
There are things like AI BOMs — like, where is the training data coming from?
From my models.
But what about things like context where you mentioned skills and MCP
and things like that?
Do we do we need like a context, building materials.
Maybe even that the AI build materials is a thing already and we scan for that.
We can we can create that for companies.
But I also think like the context or the skills that you pull in, it's
basically a dependency as well, right?
If you look at how software was developed and you pull packages
from and from from repository as your your third party
entry points, now you have that with skills.
And so the problem here now is that skills is just text,
Yeah.
And now we need to scan that to see if there are no injection in it.
If if there are no hidden hidden comments in it or even worse,
it has a hidden comment in it that is getting copied to your global memory.
And then even if you delete the skill, then it's still there.
So it's back to our basics.
As in, make sure that whatever you ingest or use is validated and vetted
and keep track of that, just like we did with our Docker containers
and with our dependencies and the code that we wrote.
So we need to be aware that that things can go south, even though
most of the stuff that are agents nowadays are creating is quite cool.
And of course, we recently announced the integration
between Snyk and Tessl, whereby we expose a lot of that data
that those scan results from Snyk within the Tessl registry.
So if you are using skill,
you can you can identify if there are threats through the Snyk
as a judge style approach to identify where those potential issues issues are.
What one piece of advice would you give people
who are using AI in an organization today as a super quick way,
a super quick way of really reducing risk within their organizations?
Have a good overview of what are you using currently?
Because if you don't know that data, you cannot protect yourself.
And secondly, make people aware of these choices
and of the of the attack vectors that are coming in.
Because I think most people that are not tech savvy
and are now using agents to build their own self aware,
if you can call it like that, the their own tooling are not aware
that if you connect this piece of data to that piece of MCP
server, that we can leak data and these kind of things.
So awareness is the first point. Amazing.
For those of you
who want to learn more about the integration,
we actually did a podcast, a full podcast episode.
So check out the AI Native Dev Podcast with Brian Vermeer.
And we did that in Atlanta. Beautiful sunny Atlanta.
Now we're in kind of cloudy London, but it's all good.
And enjoy the rest of the conference. Brian, thank you very much.
Look on now for Sam Stepanyan.
Stepanyan.
Who is the head of the OWASP London chapter.
And you're also on the global board for OWASP generally, right?
That's right. Yes.
Awesome. So.
So what are you here to learn today at at this event.
As always. Right.
We learn every day and AI is moving so quickly
and cybersecurity moving so quickly here to learn from all the peers and colleagues.
And of course for you guys, what is new in the world of AI security,
what new solutions are and what new challenges are you currently facing?
Because there is so much new stuff happening at the moment.
So also conversations around OWASP, right?
And also for everyone, obviously, because I represent OWASP
what you see is how our OWASP Top Ten for
LLMs, and the brand new OWASP Top Ten for Agentic AI is impacting people.
Because I had several conversations days ago
at the AWS conference for our products, and there are lots of
companies were just trying to get into the genetic
AI world and have like zero clue
about security issues, which can meet of that.
You mentioned the top ten, and of course, for those who don't know, is obviously
a nonprofit organisation that governs and provides a whole bunch of resources.
Sorry. Yeah.
And provides a whole bunch of best practices and great advice
for a ton of different spaces.
So the top ten for web applications
and security and web applications, mobile applications.
Cloud security approach.
And you mentioned the top ten now for AI and LLMs.
What would you say.
Kind of like the biggest mistakes that people make as as developers
or as CISOs when thinking about building using tools and AI.
The biggest mistake is they completely ignore security issues.
They jump straight in and they connect
AI directly to their production system without understanding
the consequences of it.
Yeah, and I think it's due to the huge pressure
that everyone's feeling because everyone's trying to jump on the AI train
and they're trying to, of course, use the technology and innovate.
But the fact that a lot of them are ignorant about cybersecurity issues,
which is about AI, makes it, of course, quite worrying.
It kind of reminds me the same situation that we had at the e-commerce
25 years ago when everyone said, oh, this new thing called the web.
We have to do. We have a website
and we must have an ecommerce, so we must sell things online.
The whole digital transformation, right?
Let's start taking credit cards online.
And no one thought about security and everyone started.
Getting hacked.
SQL injection was number one vulnerability back then and the same thing here.
But I was saying, oh, let's all use AI and no one thinks about, you know, basic
hygiene, things like prompt injection, but also, of course,
lots of other security concerns surrounding AI.
And we do provide OWASP
free and open source guidelines and resources and standards for you.
There was a one of the very important documents
we have which I recommend to everyone is a secure AI adoption guidelines.
So I highly encourage other organizations who are trying to adopt AI.
Check out this document which is community created the community to it
so they can understand how to adopt AI security.
And you mentioned like the pressures behind businesses who are like
not being forced necessarily, but very, very much encouraged to use
AI pressure to use AI as fast as they can.
Because realistically, businesses that don't in 1 to 2 years.
They're potentially going to be at a very strong,
very big disadvantage to those other companies that are moving so fast.
So from the point of security securities, very often seen historically
as a department that can slow down delivery, how
how much is that kind of like seen today in the world of AI is that is is security
seen as something that is is hampering the advancements of AI in organizations?
Well, that depends how you approach it.
And I would always say that no security is an enabler.
You know, it's like the brakes in your car
actually allow the cars to move faster, right?
So the same thing with AI security world,
you can innovate fast and secure manner.
But all that you need to do, you need to be aware
of all the security implications and make sure that your innovation
security experiments, they start from their isolated environment,
which is secure, right, and disconnected from your production data.
So if things go wrong, it goes minimal damage.
And obviously in the isolated environment you can actually learn
how to secure it properly for all of us
and also other industry guidelines.
And one very important point, which I'd like you to make
is also remember that AI is non-deterministic.
So let's say one thing today was a little different than tomorrow.
Another very important thing
that not many people are mentioning today is the problem with agentic
identity is the issue that at the moment, the way how
AI integrates with other things is that it acts upon humans behalf,
which makes things like traceability and audit
and logging of actions is very, very difficult
because if you grant an AI agent accessing your email box
or your behalf and it's going to go inside sending emails, sending out
spam on your behalf, or it's going to go and start
deleting and accessing or deleting customer records.
It's not Simon, it's not Simon.
AI at Tessl IO, it's Simon.
Oh yeah, it wasn't me.
It was my agent. Yeah, exactly, exactly.
Now, I was chatting with Brian Vermeer earlier,
and he was talking about one of the, one of the,
one of the first things that people do should do is understand
where organizations are using AI, how big a problem
is, almost like the governance or the understanding of
where people are using AI in their organizations today.
And there being too much, almost like shadow AI.
There's a lot of shadow.
I believe it's a big problem in organisations
where they don't have proper governance.
Yeah.
Of the IT projects
and if they allow their developers to run free and wild
and innovate on their machines
and install whatever they like and particularly specific tool and say
small organization startups,
because I usually work with organizations and highly regulated industries, such
as services, where such governance exists because of compliance.
Regulations are not all industries might have this kind of compliance regulations.
Yeah. This is why. Researching this.
And so the actual problem of finding out who is using AI,
where is this use, which models are using, how they actually access it.
It is a little bit problem because if you don't know what you have,
you cannot possibly secure it.
So do we need do we need AI compliance regulations or do
we need an upgrade to existing SOC 2, ISO and things like that with, you know.
One of the things that I'm seeing will be coming up with
something called AI Bill on material. Yeah.
So at the moment we have software.
So now there's an AI BOM emerging.
And obviously we do have an inclusive you can actually help you with that.
We have a tool which allows you to discover
your bill of materials based on the model, and also scan your repositories
and see where developers are using specific libraries.
For example, there was recently a.
Actually.
There was a supply chain attack on a very popular library called LiteLLM.
Right? Yeah.
Do you know where in your organization light is in use?
Yeah, yeah, I use it.
The vulnerable version, which was hacked. Right.
We we can now because we have played open source tools
which can actually help you to get that inventory.
But obviously there's a lot of other companies in the sector.
But the problem is that you need to understand the actual challenge.
As you mentioned, the shadow AI or shadow IT, you don't have the inventory.
You will not be able to secure it.
Do we need the inventories that you mentioned are really great,
like the software building
materials, the AI building materials, which mostly focuses on models.
Context is something that is used more and more these days, skills and contacts
that lives in developer environments, in projects.
These are things that are being used to create the code.
They're very, very key and they're just not being audited right now.
Do you feel we need is there a space for a context
bill of materials or something that should be added to an AI BOM
to include what context was used to generate this code?
I think that's a very interesting suggestion.
So we have a whole group at our studio which is currently looking at it.
And one of the things that you mentioned, skills, you actually have a new
working group which is creating a new AI agentic skills Top Ten.
Oh nice development.
I need to join this.
I need to do.
This because just like all of US projects, it's an open source project.
So we highly encourage contributions and collaborations from everyone.
Amazing. I will join and I will contribute.
Thank you very much Sam.
Always a pleasure and great to see you here.
Thank you very much. Thank you. Thank you.
Hey everyone!
Hope you're enjoying the episode so far.
Our team is working really hard behind the scenes to bring you the best guests,
so we can have the most informative conversations about agentic development,
whether that's talking about the latest
tools, the most efficient workflows, or defining best practices.
But for whatever reason, many of you have yet to subscribe to the channel.
If you're enjoying the podcast and want us to continue to bring you
the very best content.
Please do us a favor and hit that subscribe button.
It really does make a difference and lets us continue to improve
the quality of our guests and build an even better product for you.
All right, back to the episode.
Great.
So we've had a couple of chats already.
We've heard the opening keynote.
The time now is 11:20, which is just about time for Guy Podjarny's session.
Don't secure the code.
Secure the coder.
Can security keep up with the tech dev?
We've had some great chats
with Amy here and the team with a whole bunch of people on the on the expo floor.
Let's go up and see what Guy Podjarny's session is like.
And I want to introduce somebody who is quite dear to me.
I know this man for a couple of years.
Guy, please come to the stage.
Give it a big hand.
Guy will talk about obviously.
Development Guy is the founder
and CEO of Tessl and also the founder of Snyk.
He was the person who was crazy enough to hire me.
And I'm still here.
Guy will talk about definitely talk
about things like skills, but also about how agentic development
has evolved and can security actually keep up with this?
I think it goes well, along with my introduction
and the introduction that Joe gave.
So with without further ado and not killing all the lights on stage,
I will leave it up to you. Thank you. Guy.
Thanks. Hello everyone. Can you hear me?
Is this coming through?
Do we have the slides up?
Cool, cool.
So, yeah, I'm Guy Podjarny, I'm the founder of Snyk.
The chairman of the board.
But I'm here with a different hat here, which is a couple of years ago,
I fell in love with AI
and went to found Tessl, which is in the AI development space.
And in that a lot of our work focuses on sort of
securing for the agent era or in general.
How do you develop software in the sort of agentic era?
What's the the new paradigm that we have to adapt to?
And security is an aspect of that.
And in that a lot of the kind of the core new world
moves us from software development and security revolving
around the implementation, revolving around the code to revolving around
instructions and intent, because we're now driving and guiding agents.
And so that's kind of the
theme of my kind of points over here, is We need to move from securing the code
to securing the coder, securing the the agent.
So it's no secret that AI is transforming software development.
And while we had a
bunch of very good examples here about non software development flows on it,
I think software development is a good harbinger.
Sort of like Canary to say this will happen to all knowledge work.
So I'll focus very much about that.
And in software development we've gone from
from AI augmented software development that was pioneered by Copilot
and then cursor that it's more about aiding your coding.
And this helps you write code to AI native software development.
That is more about delegation.
It's more about the agents in which you're asking the agent
to do a task for you, and it goes on and and performs it better or not.
And this agent development is where everything has consolidated towards.
And so today, I think, again, not a controversial statement to say
we should focus on what is how do we secure agentic development
as the mental model for us.
And the development is amazing.
It's powerful.
A single person can do so much to it, but it introduces a bunch of new challenges
as compared to how we've been dealing with software security before.
And again, this is security and software development as a whole.
And I'll mention three big ones here that I'll focus on in this talk.
One is it's non-deterministic.
So we use the software that if it compiled once it will compile again.
Right.
We're used to to things that that are the risk
that we can say this now works I scanned it.
It didn't have it. I'll scan it again — it still does not have it.
It's the same findings that I get.
And that's no longer the case with agents Or with agents.
We have to make do with the fact that these are non-deterministic creatures.
We have to get statistical.
We have to say, well, it works nine times out of ten, 99 times out of 100.
How do we handle that? How do we even find out?
Second is, as
mentioned, it revolves around intent or instructions, not code.
So what is the sort of new unit of software that we need to secure here?
How do we evolve our security
and improve our security of securing the coder?
So that's a new challenge for us. And I'll talk about that.
And then lastly,
as you might have noticed, it changes at a certain kind of rapid clip.
And so software development as a whole and the need for security
and a bunch of other aspects of the knowledge
domain are moving and changing faster than ever before.
So how do we deal with that?
So there are clearly many aspects of agent
development that I don't cover here, but I'll focus on these three.
So the first and
biggest one is the fact that agent dev is non-deterministic.
And that really reminds me of this sort of DevOps ethos that we have, right.
In DevOps. We were saying if it moves, measure it.
If it doesn't move, measure it in case it moves, know.
It's like the most statistical creatures that we have in our disposal
today is these servers that are sometimes up and sometimes down.
They're not really behaving as they should.
And so in this world you have to say, well, you can't optimize like the,
the learning from there was you can't optimize what you can't measure.
Right. It's a pretty simple statement, but it's a good one to remember.
So how do we measure agent behavior.
How do we think about this.
Well, generally
there are a lot of very evolved ways to do evaluations or evals in AI world.
But typically what you would do is you would create a task for the agent,
hey, agent, here is a task and I'll use 11 labs
intentionally starting from non-security.
So 11 labs is a very successful London
based kind of text to speech
lab or AI lab, and they have an ability to generate music.
And so we can give it a task, for instance, in this case
a dynamic soundtrack generator for a game studio.
And then you define up front some criteria to say, what does good look like?
Like what is what is correct implementation of this.
And then you run that task across the agent.
And what this plot shows is it shows five different scenarios.
We have our sort of dynamic soundtrack over here,
but I have five others in areas that I ran each of them ten times and I scored it.
And you can see a few things
like already you're a little bit more informed, for instance.
You see the lines are not very high.
The scores that the the agent got for this is not very good.
And that's because the music API is relatively new.
So it's not well represented in the, in the sort of the model right,
in the weights.
And so they don't really know how to handle it.
And so that's one problem.
The second is that you see the dots are all over the place.
Like we asked the agent to do the same thing again.
Again sometimes you see kind of like normal scatter.
Sometimes they'd do better, sometimes they'd do worse, maybe within a range.
And you have some other cases where it kind of hit the mark.
Right.
It sort of guessed correctly one time or two times and then it doesn't.
These others.
So we have this mess and it's very hard to work with that.
So clearly said, well, how can I make it better.
How can I make it work better?
How do I kind of train the sort of agents, how do I harness them?
And harness is actually a different word.
I didn't say that. Ignore that word.
And then and it's sort of the most common kind of way to do that is with context.
And the most common unit of context that is used today are skills.
So these are basically markdown files a little bit more with some structure.
But these are bits of information for the agent to use
to be able to perform this task.
And we need to remember that knowledge is not the same as intelligence.
The the models can be brilliant and very, very capable,
but if they don't know something, oftentimes they just can't do it.
Or it's just mighty inefficient for them to do that so they can figure it out.
But they will be there will be statistics there.
And so in this case, we have an 11 labs music skill that helps explain the API.
And so when we run, when we use that we indeed
see that for our dynamic soundtrack generator.
And I'm using Tessl here to do the evaluations.
You see that without context it didn't do a bunch of things.
It did.
It used the deprecated package, it didn't import it correctly and all that.
And with the skill with the context, it got it done.
So it got a 50% average without the skill, versus 98% with it.
So it's good we managed to correct it.
And if we run this across the line, we see in some cases we just solved it.
It just basically now is sufficiently good to fairly consistently do the task.
And in other cases it's still slightly varied, but it's further up,
so it is more capable of doing that task.
So this is the type of way in which you evolve
and you improve your agents ability to do something.
This is a security event.
So how do we talk about this for security?
Well, let's take another example.
Code guard is something that Cisco created and donated.
And it's basically a bunch of sort of OWASP security
kind of rules packaged up into a skill.
And and it helps kind of these
AI developers, these agents develop more secure code.
So let's put that to the test.
I created six different evaluation scenarios.
And I specifically focused on authorization.
How well did you handle the security of authorization in this code.
So for instance hey agent, create an access control
test suite for a project management API and then created a bunch of scores for it.
And I did it with and without code Guard.
And as you would expect, it got better.
So without Code Guard, just as is, the agent scored 48%
on my kind of authorization criteria, sort of a scorecard.
So not awesome.
And if it had these instructions nearly 1.6 x the improvement on.
So it got a fair bit better because there was a bunch of guides
about how to sort of code securely, including authorization.
So that's that's good. That's already useful.
However, if I took all the information in Code Guard
that has a
lot of security practices in it, and I shrunk it down to just the
authentication and authorisation related bits, which are, I think about sort of 5%
of the total content.
If I remember correctly, it did a lot better.
It went to 98%.
And this is this is sort of a core thing to remember,
which is more context is not necessarily better. Right.
If I sat here and I told you 100 things, no matter how sort of brilliant or dumb
they were,
you will notice you'll give less attention to each one of them than if I told you.
Three and attention is a scarce resource with humans and with models.
And so choosing and managing.
What is it that you say that actually matters that the model doesn't
already know,
like not wasteful information that there's no point in saying
is important and is a part of that competency.
Taking that a little bit further,
you know,
if this is the graph that shows the same numbers
from before of code guard, not guard, you also might be surprised
to hear the different agents respond to the same information differently.
So this is an example of the same test.
In fact a whole it's literally the same execution.
And what you can see is different models respond differently.
Opus and sonnet at the top they get about the same results.
Even though opus is more intelligent, it is more expensive.
So if you use the opus for this specific task, you kind of wasted money
and probably time because you could do the same with sonnet.
And what you can see is codex and cursor.
They respond even differently and it doesn't matter which one is better.
Like it does matter eventually.
But that's not my point, but rather
the fact that different agents, again, almost like humans, listen differently.
And so you want to know that your instructions
are effective, are not wasteful for the agents that you are using.
So that's kind of core point here is if we want to secure
agents, we want to use skills to help them secure code or write secure code.
We have to learn how to measure that.
And how do you how do you build good context.
Like how do you how do you evolve it?
How do you create kind of quality context, you know, how to build.
So where to talk a little bit
about the fact that you generate you create a skill, you evaluate it,
and then once you've evaluated, you can optimize it
until you kind of get a better and better guidance for that agent.
And then you need to distribute that or communicate it.
If you want to use the human mode to the agents and observe what has happened.
And the observe is important.
If the evals are kind of like your tests, once you've got something working
and you make a modification, how do you know you're not breaking it?
How do you know you're evolving it?
How do you know if you can use a cheaper model or not?
You have to be able to evaluate, but eventually
your test will go out of out of sync.
They would not represent reality if you don't also observe
what is happening.
So we call this the context development lifecycle.
And as you build
good context, you can use that context across the software development lifecycle.
So we think the CDLC is where us humans should live.
We should be building good context that guides the agents.
And then we should apply that to the SDLC where the agents should work.
And the same context,
the same instruction can be applied end to end in the development process.
Same as like a great developer on the team will use the same knowledge
to define a product feature, write the code, troubleshoot something,
ship it to production, troubleshoot an incident, etc. etc.
the same knowledge is useful
across the board, so the skills represent that knowledge.
And of course, from a security lens perspective,
we can now use that to secure different steps.
So this is this is how you should write secure code at the beginning.
This is what I want to audit in the code review to highlight to you.
This is what I want to get on.
This is what I want to inspect when an incident occurred.
So all of these things can be represented in skills that we use across the SDLC.
So this is non-deterministic.
It's kind of my biggest point to make.
And as we as we learn how to evaluate those.
The second point is
we've been talking more and more about these skills
and we're sort of optimizing these skills and we're developing these skills.
And I think it's useful to start
thinking about skills in terms of their own security as a unit of software.
Right. It looked like a markdown file.
They look like a notion document or like a confluence document.
But the way we process them is we execute them by the agent
or the agent execute them.
So really, I think we're well served, especially from a security lens,
to think about them as a unit of software, not just as a piece of text.
And we have like a lot of indications of that today.
Right?
We have the Snyk study, and there were very many others
that showed, especially in the open Claude world,
where a lot of skills were malicious, literally attackers putting in things
that are trying to make the, the, the agent to do something it shouldn't.
Here's an example of a malicious skill.
This is from the Tessl
registry scanned by Snyk, where it had a bunch of that it down.
And while most of your URLs were just standard blockchain
APIs, one of them was suddenly downloading a password protected zip.
Fishy doesn't sound right.
Okay, that's potentially a malicious skill.
There's a bunch of things
we can do, clearly imperfect, but we can try to detect malicious skills.
There are also vulnerable skills.
What's a vulnerable skill?
For instance, a skill that uses insecure credential handling.
It asks the user to put API keys inside, or it makes MCP calls
with sort of plain vanilla tokens for it.
So that's an example of something that is insecure behavior.
It's vulnerable to exfiltrate some information outside.
There's also like new types of flaws that you might have in what I
this is not an industry term, but what I like to think of as negligence skills.
So these are skills that do not have
some basic safety instructions inside of them.
For example: check this into a repository.
Do not make it a public repository.
If you cannot commit to the repository, fail.
Don't like go off and sort of send it in another way.
So a bunch of these types of examples are very real examples.
And we have cases where we've had agents.
There's a behavior called reward seeking which is you ask them to do something
and they're really, really, really keen to do it.
And so they go up and they try to do everything they can,
and they escape their sandbox
and they delete files and they do whatever it is to please you.
And so you have to define a little bit of these safety instructions.
It's kind of similar to what Brian's example was on.
Right to say do not disclose information that makes it at least less negligent.
And then again, similar to software, there's a question about supply chain.
How do you consume these skills today?
The reality is that people just consume them out of GitHub repo.
They download them from wherever. You have no idea that it happened.
You have no idea where it's there.
Then they check them in to their repositories.
Different agents read them from different places,
so you might check them in seven times the different folders within your repo.
It's not.
It's early, it's fine, will improve.
But for now it's not awesome.
So you have to think a little bit
about supply chain. So all of those become obvious
once you think about skills as units of software.
So what do we want to do here.
Like what is what is enterprise grade
kind of skill governance skill usage on it.
This is a nascent space.
I'll give you the lens on it because this is our world.
We think you need to think about
three different elements of of evolving this piece of software.
First is governance and security.
Know what the hell is going on?
Try to sort of audit the use of it — like, you've posted skills.
Did anybody install them?
Constrain the use of skills.
So people download skills always through this sort of centralized path.
Again, not that dissimilar
to what you should be doing with NPM libraries or whatever.
And so you have to know about the governance.
If you can't do that, you really oftentimes cannot roll out.
Once you rolled out, you have a need to standardize and allow reuse.
If three different people created a skill
to review code, and a fourth person comes along and says,
I want to use a skill like, first of all, where do they find it?
Second is, how do they know which of the three to change?
If I created a skill and then one of you came in
and proposed the modification, how do you know if it's good or not good.
If I now 100 people are using this skill and I'm
going to make a change to the skill, how do I know that I'm not breaking it?
And so there's a bunch of this notion
of standardization, of reusability that you have to create a measure.
And then lastly, and this is the holy grail is continuous optimization.
You want to know that this is that CDLC — that we want the continuous optimisation.
You want to observe what has happened.
Did the agent fail?
Did the user need to correct the agent and take that information
and route that back to be able to evolve the skill, create new eval scenarios?
And that is the holy grail.
And the companies that are at the cutting edge are doing this right.
They are creating that optimization.
Most organizations are quite far from it.
And so that's why this is oftentimes the sequence.
I'd be
remiss if I didn't do a little bit of a Tessl plug over here.
So that's oftentimes what we help you do.
We have a platform in which, on one hand from a
from a development perspective, we help you collaboratively develop skills
that allow developers to discover and install those quality skills
and then observe what has happened, learn from that and create new paths.
And then within that we have these these controls.
So we have the ability to now make sure with Snyk we scan every skill
that gets published into the into the registry.
So you know that it's not malicious.
Similarly, when you install we have controls about scan from us.
We have analytics about who's using what.
And then lastly for the sort of these nascent agent enablement
teams, these platform teams, developer experience team AI enablement teams
that are that own successful rollout of agents in the organization.
We give them a bunch of these abilities
to eliminate duplicates, drive skill usage, optimize costs.
I like to say that agentic development is cheaper than expensive.
It's like very cheap at the beginning
because a single person can do so much and then you get the bill.
It's not that awesome.
So you start thinking,
as we use agents more and more, what is the sort of the cost?
And those, of course, you know, a moment with the Snyk hat on,
we have some amazing other aspects
of securing the agent behavior itself and its runtime in Evo.
and I'm sure you'll hear more about this over here as well.
And then to close off, I want to talk about the third bullet,
which is agentic development moves faster than ever
and security must become agentic to keep up.
Sounds very familiar to me from the Snyk early days.
And when I when I hearken back to what happened, the Snyk roots.
You think if you're a graybeard like me, you think about the change
that happened there when we went from waterfall
to cloud and some behaviors, some manual processes
and such were tolerated in waterfall and were no longer tolerated in cloud.
The idea that before any piece of software will shift,
someone will manually audit it was tolerated.
You know, like the best teams automated the security scanning of it,
but most people manually audited, so the average team did not.
In cloud. That cannot be the case once you're in DevOps.
Once you're in that continuous, you have to automate that scanning.
I think we're facing now the same thing,
which is some things are tolerated in cloud.
The best teams are automating them.
They're sort of reviewing them. They're auto improving them.
But most teams are not.
And they're no longer going to be tolerated in agents.
So there's a little bit of like
the future is here, but it's not evenly distributed.
We should think about all these things that are like
the paper cuts that we have, the places in which like, you know what?
As a security person, I will triage these vulnerabilities for my developers
or I will, you know, maybe we'll only fix the ones that are truly glaring.
We're not going to fix the rest.
Many of these things are just no longer an option.
So you have to think about how do we improve them.
And there's a long list of those.
There are many, many, many things that go from nice to have to,
must have from indeed prioritization to automating upgrades
to detection of supply chain manipulations.
Like there's just so many things.
This is really just a tiny sample set.
And the good news is that for each one of those agents can really,
really help in making these automated like it's agents all the way down.
Right?
You can build agents upon agents that will do a bunch
of these different steps, and that allows us to scale.
And So we find ourselves in this kind of carrot and stick mode security.
If it doesn't become agentic, it will never keep up.
We will fail. The attackers are becoming agentic.
They're moving faster than ever.
The development, like the business, has to be agentic to be able to to develop
and we have to keep up over there.
So if we don't become agentic, there's a bit of a, you know,
like you're going to be in trouble.
But if you do, if we do become agentic in the world,
then we can actually fix application security.
We can actually fix those things that we've long wanted and tried to get
developers to do on a consistent fashion, which to me is exciting. So
I'm excited by the new future.
I'm slightly daunted.
I think there's a lot of need to change just to plug.
We have a conference in a couple of weeks here: AI Native Dev Con.
It's running here in London June 1st and second.
If it's all about agentic development, adoption like real world scenarios
actually in kind of organizations that have it, if you want to check it out.
I think Brian might be speaking.
And also I think we stole you to a different one in the previous one
and a lot of learning on it.
Would love to see you there if you'd like.
That's it for me. Thank you.
What a day. At the AI Security Summit.
We had some great discussions on the Tessl booth.
We had some wonderful chats on the showroom floor.
We had some great sessions, guy in particular, super enlightening
about securing the coder, not the code from AI Security Summit.
Wonderful day.
Thank you very much.
Snyk. And everyone here.
The AI Native Dev is brought to you by the package manager for skills and context.
Your hosts are Guy Podjarny and me, Simon Maple.
Our producer is Tom Dowler.
The AI Native Dev is not just a podcast, it's a community.
And we host monthly meetups at the Tessl offices in central London.
Visit tessl.io/community to learn more and I hope to see you there.